Richard Adem

UX Engineer

Email: Work portfolio: Linkedin: Github: richy486@gmail.com richardadem.com linkedin.com/richardade <u>m</u> github.com/richy486

Summary

I am a UX Engineer with over 13 years professional experience creating software with a focus on UX and architecture. I have been developing iOS software in Objective-C and later Swift since the platform was released and published dozens of apps in the App Store.

I currently work at Google London, on the Arts & Culture Team.

Focus Languages: Swift, Objective-C, C++

I specialize in rapid prototyping, working closely with the design and experience leads to create highly polished UI with beautiful transitions and intuitive interactions.

Education: Bachelor of Computer Science -

Charles Sturt University,

Australia

Experience

2018 - Present Google Arts & Culture, London

- UX Engineer, Production
 - I write production code for the AR art experiences, working in a cross-functional team of 3D artists, product leads, designers and engineers.

Google Search & Assistant, Mountain View

- UX Engineer, Prototyping
 - Worked within the UX team in rapid prototypes on iOS.
 - Responsible for presenting new UI features and products to VP level stakeholders.

2016 - 2018 Code and Theory, New York

- Senior iOS Developer
 - I managed the international iOS team, streamlining the process and leading the team to be the highest performing development team at the agency.
 - I created a structured iOS architecture using Redux and Functional Reactive Programming patterns and implemented complex animations from designers using CoreAnimation.

2015 - 2016 Small Planet, Brooklyn

- Senior iOS Developer
 - I worked on the FanDuel Turbo competitive gaming app, rewrote networking code to keep it in sync and prevent dropouts.

2015 Triptale, Copenhagen

- iOS Developer
 - Created a modular iOS and Android app generating system for white label tourism apps.

2014 - 2015 Isobar, Melbourne

- iOS Developer
 - I worked on a variety of apps for the entertainment and real estate sectors and brought data syncing time down on an app from 3 minutes to 5 seconds by consolidating network requests.

2013 - 2014 The Royals, Melbourne

- iOS Developer
 - Variety of iOS apps for clients including visualizations of 3d landscapes with dynamic cities based on popularity of twitter hashtags.

2011 - 2013 Vortilla Digital, Melbourne

- iOS Developer
 - Variety of iOS apps for clients including a real estate floor plan designer app.

2010 - 2011 DMG Radio, Melbourne

- Web and iOS Developer
 - Developed and maintained all iOS apps for multiple radio stations.

2007 - 2009 Acheron Design, Melbourne

- Game Developer
 - Variety of video games for popular consoles including simulation of cricket games that produced realistic scores that was used in subsequent releases.